

# Lukáš Buňát





🛅 Full-Stack Developer 🖥 Big Data Engineer 🖓 Business Consultant







+420 731 277 533



bunat.cz



bunatl



**lukasbunat** 

Full-Stack Developer with the primary focus on front-end with 4+ years of experience in web/software development and data science. I have an educational background in Computer Science and Business Informatics at many different universities all over the world. I thrive on multicultural teams and enjoy resolving everyday challenges using my analytical thinking and problem-solving skills.



### **Technical Skills**

	Front-End	React.js 16.12, JavaScript ES6/2017, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass		
Full-Stack	Back-End	AWS services, serverless, Node.js, express.js, apache2, nginx		
technologies	Database	MongoDB (Mongoose, Monk), DynamoDB, MySQL, MS SQL Server, lowdb		
	Other	Yarn, npm, webpack, parcel, react testing library, Jest, postman		
Data Science	Python, R, SQL SSIS/SSAS, BI, Tableau, Hadoop, PySpark, Rapid Miner, Hive, Spark, Jupyter			
Collaboration	GIT (GitHub), JIRA, Trello, Slack, Asana, G Suite, MS Teams, Office 365			



**Freelance** 

### **Work Experience**

#### Web dev, tutor & consultant 05/2015 - Present Prague, Czech Republic

- I consult businesses to digitalize their processes
- I am implementing (web) automatization tools
- Build and maintain business React/WordPress websites
- I tutor university students in programming & math
- Implementing additional web apps' functionalities

Video services specialist 05/2018-05/2019 O2 Czech Republic a.s. Prague, Czech Republic

- I helped to deliver the O2TV platform with 500K users
- **O2TV** is a content streaming platform built with ReactJS and supported with other JAVA SE/EE & C applications
- I integrated an audio/video player for Prague's city hall
- I maintain and develop other internal application
- The platform is available on: https://www.o2tv.cz/

#### 10/2017 - 12/2017 **Big Data Analyst** Madrid, Spain **Comillas Pontifical University**

- Analyzed Spain's power distribution system to discover consumption patterns using clustering techniques
- Analyzed data were stored in **Hadoop**, I processed them with **Spark** (for faster processing) and I used **Hive** for SQL-like interface. Code is written in PySpark
- The findings (visualized in pandas) allowed to pre-assign the necessary resources in each range of time or season

From 2014 to 2019 I had been working as a volunteer tutor at international student club at CTU.



### Featured Projects

#### **Portalo**

- A portal that links internal and external web apps into a single portal. User module allows manage employees and their information store in a database
- I created this project as part of my diploma thesis and distributed it as an open-source code
- Front-end part is written in ReactJS with Ant Design and back-end using GraphQL with DynamoDB, Lambda, IAM, Amplify and Cognito services. Hosted on AWS.

#### **EconMetrics CZ**

- The application provides company profiling, economical scoring and other multicriteria analysis using gathered and structured available public data
- Reports from EconMetrics can be used either by individuals or companies
- API enables automatization for 3rd parties
- Currently is project in development

#### **Company Business Intelligence Analysis**

- I designed and created a database in MS SQL Server based on the structure of the given raw data
- With data pumps I imported raw data from excel, txt, csv and MS Access files, using ETL operations in SQL SSIS
- Based on stored data, I built OLAP cube in SQL SSAS and graphically represented them in Tableau





New creative and innovative approaches to problem solving



Very good (cross-culture) communication for constructive teamwork



Enthusiastic and passionate about learning new things and technologies



Decisiveness and good decision-making (even uder pressure) & leadership



Effective time managment to ensure tasks' deadlines are met



## **Education**

Unive	rsity, Year(s) of Study	Field of study, Faculty	Location
STOLA EAOLO	University of Economics and Business 2019 - Present	Information systems and technologies  MSc. Graduate (Ing.), exp.06/2021  Faculty of informatics and statistics	Prague, Czech Republic
	Czech Technical University 2019	Open Informatics Faculty of Electrical Engineering	Prague, Czech Republic
<b>B</b> B	University of Finance and Administration 2018-2019	Applied Informatics Undergraduate (Bc.) Faculty of Economics	Prague, Czech Republic
	Czech Technical University  2014–2018	Information Systems and Management Faculty of Information Technology	Prague, Czech Republic
THE REAL PROPERTY OF THE PARTY	Kyungpook National University  2017	Exchange studies  College of IT Engineering	Daegu, South Korea
	Indian Institute of Technology Madras 2016	Exchange studies  Department of Computer Science	Chennai, India
STANDOCCULINATION OF THE PROPERTY OF THE PROPE	Delft University of Technology 2016	Case study of Earthquakes in Netherland The ATHENS Programme	P Delft, Netherlands
	Mayflower College of English 2012	Summer language school	Plymouth, United Kingdom



# **Certificates**



CISCO Academy

CCNA 1 (2013)



Autodesk





KFN of UNESCO

Cross Culture Awereness Programme